Hello Friends, I am Mahesh from TrekBook India
our todays subject is Car Insurance Policies
which are the Top 5 Car Insurance Companies in India
this year in 2021 and Why?
that study I will present with reasons
now this study I have done for my own car
& this month only I have renewed my cars insurance
so that is why this study was important for me
so I thought, same study will be useful for you all
so lets move on ...
so which is my car?
so my car is Maruti Cia 1.5L Alpha AT Smart Hybrid
which I bought in Dec 2018
so it have been over 3 years now
for this IDV (Insured Declared Value) I have taken 5,92,000 Rs
this has been calculated by Insurance company
so all those quotations I have taken from online companies for comparison purpose
for all I have kept IDV same, so that it becomes easy to compare
what is the Premium & which company I should select
I have specifically taken Zero Depreciation
now what is difference in Comprehensive Vs Zero Depreciation
that I will show you quickly
and in case after watching this total study
selecting any insurance company, like I will be telling you the Top 5
so I suggest
what you have to do is
approved & associated garages of the company you select
check how many are there in your area
now what is importance of this?
that if you have approve garage, you will not have any difficulty
the garage person will pick your car from accident location
and will return it after the work is completed
billing and everything will be handled directly with the insurance company
and the approved garage
so for this it is important that you should look for approved garages in your area
now simple - lets see the comparison
shall I go for comprehensive or Zero-Dep?
because premium for both are different
as example if comprehensive insurance is 8,000 Rs
in that case Zero depreciation may cost you 12,000 Rs or 15,000 Rs
there is difference in costs
so any time comprehensive policy premium will be less
as compared to the Zero depreciation premium
claim settlement amount you will get lesser in comprehensive insurance
because
if your plastic parts gets damaged during accident
then you will get only 50% of plastic part cost
other parts amount also you will get less
because if your car is 2,3,4,5 years old
as per the car age, depreciation will increase
so in hand amount
if expenses are 50,000 Rs, you will not get full repair amount
but you will get depreciated amount only
so for this reason - which one should we take?
so as per me, if you have New car, then comprehensive insurance is more than sufficient
suppose its first or second year
then you can select comprehensive insurance
suppose I take Zero depreciation insurance in second year
which I generally prefer, since I don't like any problem & get 100% amount
if your car is 3,4,5 years old we should go for Zero depreciation - this is my personal opinion again
so lets see the insurance provider in the upper area
and you are policy holder
left side is your car
and in case you meet an accident
then the other side car
with which you meet an accident
car or any other thing
that is called as third party
so in India legally Third part insurance is mandatory
if your car is one road in India
then Third party insurance is a MUST
so at least you need to do that
& you have choice of comprehensive or Zero dep insurance
so in case you have gone for Third part only
so you are able to see - the car you met an accident
that car will get complete amount
but the damage of your own car
expenses will have to be bared by you
so damage on self car is not covered in only Third party insurance
in case you go for comprehensive cover
in comprehensive cover
you will get repair cost of your car, but as I told you earlier
you will get less amount considering depreciation value
and in case you select Zero Dep
which is the best as per me
in that 100% of the damage
like if its plastic part
for which 50% amount gets cut in comprehensive
that you will get full amount in Zero Dep
so now lets move on to ..
whatever I have taken for my Maruti Ciaz automatic
for the IDV 5,92,000 Rs
I took quotes from different companies
just see the list of companies, Acko, Raheja, United India, National insurance, Navi insurance, SBI
Universal sompo, new India insurance, chola, TATA AIG, kotak gen insu
digit, Bajaj allianze
and Shri Ram
so I have taken Quotation from all these companies
some are Government companies & others private
so the first column you are able to see
it is basic own damage premium
Okay?
second column is Third party premium
so base cover Point A I am talking about
base cover consists of basic own damage premium + third party premium
Third party you can see 3,221 Rs is constant for all
as I told you this is mandatory part
first part is optional part
second part is point B which is Discounts
so the No Claim Bonus given by each company to me
that I have shown
and other discounts
like if you see Sri-ram
then on basic damage premium
they have given discount of 16,000 Rs
for me important is how much I have to pay after discount
then column C shows Add-Ons
so in add-ons I have majorly taken Zero Depreciation
you get difference add-ons
but what I say that at least you should take zero dep
so that I have taken
for that how much cost gets added is shown in this column
I have written 1 Rs in front of Acko
Actually the offer I got from Acko
in which they gave me Zero dep in Zero Rs as a special offer (since I bought in 1 month advance)
so you may also get this offer
you can just check
I have given link in the video description
you can click and check if you get some offer
so check it
and misc or other benefits, some companies have given different offers like
free towing option, you need to pay additional premium
Acko have got that covered which I will show you
so final column A+B+C is total premium what you have to pay actually
so that package premium I have written
over & above you need to add 18% GST
& final premium is highlighted with specific colour
so you can see this is the final amount you need to pay to the insurance company
Okay?
so for Acko I need to pay 8,734 Rs
final insurance. Okay?
now the most important thing
that insurance I am getting in 8734 Rs that is correct
what is important is that in case the car really meets an accident
then does the company easily pays you easily?
that is very much important
otherwise accident will happen
repair will be done & you will keep discussing with the company on bills
& that becomes what is called as Claim Settlement Ratio
so claim settlement ration I have taken from
IDRA website (Insurance Development Authority of India)
which is government body
so data you will get is accurate, I am not sure what they can show in advertisements
so last 2 columns show IRDA data
one data is of 2018-19
second is 2019-2020
so you can see - the Top 5 companies I am taking about
which includes Acko,
Raheja QBE
United India Insurance
National Insurance & Navi Insurance
for these companies 2019-2020 IRDA claim settlement ratio
these are above 95%
that is why I am saying these are top 5 companies Plus
plus SBI Gen insurance is also there
whose claim settlement ratio was 92% as per IRDA
that I am keeping as runner-up
remaining companies settlement ratios you can see on your own
that how much settlement companies are providing to people
so before giving money you should also see
higher premium does not mean higher settlement ratio, that's what I want to show here
that is main purpose of this table
so you can see Acko insurance is lowest for me
& their claim settlement ratio is 97.58% which is very good
in my personal perspective because
guarantee of getting money to me is more
that is the reason why I have selected Acko
some columns are showing settlement ratios over 100%
why it is like that?
you can think and tell me reason in comments section
if your thinking is right I will answer
I will like you to put answers in comments
so this is the riddle for you
so Acko advantage which I have got in ~8500 Rs
you can see last year I paid premium or this year Tata AIG premium
so last year I paid something around 17,000 Rs
this years quotation was @17K only I got
but now I got insurance in half price
plus I have selected company which has got higher settlement ratio compared to Tata AIG
okay, so that is the advantage
so lets see what all I have got in Acko Advantage
so FREE pickup from accident site or home I got
I have got this in very less premium that you need to keep in mind
repairs at owners network of expert garages
so tie-up garage is going to do the repairs
I have got 3 day repair guarantee
I get cab voucher of 500 Rs if car remains in their garage for more than 3 days
then I will get cab voucher of 500 Rs per day
okay, then car drop after repairs
& cashless hassle free processing
so I need not do anything, of course
1,000 Rs processing fee which every insurance company asks for
that is common across all insurance companies
irrespective of which company you are choosing from
now what all is covered under this
main - accident damages are covered, that's the purpose
then fire is covered
in case of theft, you will get IDV price
calamities like earthquake or riots are covered
then obviously third party which is basic
death, injury or property damage will be given by the insurance company
then consumables also covered in Zero Dep
nut, bolt, lubricant in case of say engine damage is also covered
zero dep obviously I have selected in this special plan
& in case of car owners death you will get compensation
now it is important to see what is not covered in this
so non-accidental damages
normal wear and tear
like brakes or tyre wear are not covered under this insurance
in fact if you want these they you have to pay additional premium
but I think that is stupidity because
you keep on debating with the insurance company on reasons
so I will not prefer that
consequential loss, indirect damage
if another person dies and there are indirect loses then they are not covered
tomorrow in case war happens
nuclear war or normal war damages your car , then its not covered
if you do illegal driving
if you drunk and drive
or drive without driving license
or you are driving illegally like driving in BRT lane
in case of accident you will not get insurance amount
tyre, tube, normal wear and tear nobody gives
and then
preexisting damages are not covered in insurance (inspection will be done by the company)
and one more point is
in case your car is private
like my car is private & I gave it to someone for commercial use (rent)
& car meets accident which was used for commercial purpose, you will not get insurance amount
and one more clause is voluntary deductible
what it means that
if - like I have taken Acko insurance
if I get repaired in Acko approved garages then I have to pay only 1,000 Rs
in case I go to my preferred garage which is not in list of Acko approved garages
then I have to give 5,000 Rs
this I have agreed for
but in case I don't want this clause then
in that case the insurance premium of 8500 becomes 12500 Rs
so I have not gone for it
so that's all guys
as per me I have told the important thing that
claim settlement ratio should be good
and premium should be lowest
and affiliate garages should be available in your area
so considering these 3 factory I bought Acko insurance
so what I have done
for quick reference
my previous insurance was Tata AIG
so Tata AIG & Acko insurance links I have given in video description
you can click and get quotations from both and compare on your own
and then decide which insurance you want to take
so if you have liked this video - do tell me in comments
if you have different subject in which you are interested please let me know and I will try
chalo .. bye for now
thank you